Guide to the Paul Davidson Papers, 1961-2004 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Paul Davidson papers 1961-2004 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Davidson, Paul, 1930-
13.5 linear feet Extent: Apprpoximately 10,125 Items
Economist on the faculty at the University of Tennessee and editor of the Journal of Post Keynesian Economics. The Paul Davidson Papers span the years 1961-2004 and document his professional career and interests, including post-Keynesian economics; international monetary payments and global employment policies; monetary theory; income distribution; and energy economics. The collection almost exclusively consists of correspondence files, with the exception of a few clippings and speeches folders. The most notable group of correspondents are his fellow post-Keynesians such as Victoria Chick, Alfred Eichner, John Kenneth Galbraith, Geoff Harcourt, Jan Kregel, Hyman Minsky, Basil Moore, Luigi Pasinetti, Joan Robinson, Anthony Thirlwall, and Sidney Weintraub. Other correspondents of note include Philip Arestis, Peter Bernstein, Robert Clower, Robert Eisner, Sir John Hicks, Allan H. Meltzer, Edward Nell, Don Patinkin, James Tobin, and Paul Samuelson. Other large amounts of correspondence and other materials relate to Davidson's editorial work with many major economics journals, including the Journal of Post Keynesian Economics, which he founded; these folders typically contain correspondence between Davidson, journal referees, and authors.
RL.00289
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Paul Davidson Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2000, 2002, and 2008.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1930 October 23 Born in Brooklyn, New York
1950 B.S., Brooklyn College (now Brooklyn College of the City University of New York).
1951-1952 Instructor in physiological chemistry, University of Pennsylvania
1953-1955 U.S. Army Military Service
1955 M.B.A., City College (now City College of the City University of New York)
1955-1958 Instructor in Economics
1958-1960 Assistant Professor of Economics, Rutgers University
1959 Ph.D., University of Pennsylvania
1960-1961 Assistant director of Economics Division, Continental Oil Co., Houston, Texas
1960 Published Theories of Aggregate Income Distribution, Rutgers University Press
1961-1963 Assistant Professor of Economics, University of Pennsylvania
1963-1966 Associate Professor of Economics, University of Pennsylvania
1964-1966 Consultant, Resources for the Future
1966-1987 Professor of Economics, Rutgers University
1966-1975 Associate Director of Bureau of Economic Research, Rutgers University
1972 Published Money and the Real World, Macmillan
1973 Ford Foundation Energy Policy Project
1975-1978 Chairman of New Brunswick Department of Economics and Allied Sciences and Director of Bureau of Economic Research, Rutgers University
1978- Founded and served as editor (with Sidney Weintraub) of Journal of Post Keynesian Economics
1981 Published International Money and the Real World, Macmillan
1987- Distinguished Professor of Economics, University of Tennessee, Knoxville
1987 Published with son, Greg Davidson, Economics for a Civilized Society, Norton
1991 Published Controversies in Post Keynesian Economics, Edward Elgar
1991 Published with J. Kregel Economic Problems of the 1990s: Less Developed Countries, Europe and the United States, Edward Elgar
2007 Publication of John Maynard Keynes, Palgrave/Macmilan Publishers, London and New York
Collection Overview
The Paul Davidson Papers span the years 1961-2004 and document his professional career and interests, including post-Keynesian economics; international monetary payments and global employment policies; monetary theory; income distribution; and energy economics. The collection almost exclusively consists of correspondence files, with the exception of a few clippings and speeches folders. The most notable group of correspondents are his fellow post-Keynesians such as Victoria Chick, Alfred Eichner, John Kenneth Galbraith, Geoff Harcourt, Jan Kregel, Hyman Minsky, Basil Moore, Luigi Pasinetti, Joan Robinson, Anthony Thirlwall, and Sidney Weintraub. Other correspondents of note include Philip Arestis, Peter Bernstein, Robert Clower, Robert Eisner, Sir John Hicks, Allan H. Meltzer, Edward Nell, Don Patinkin, James Tobin, and Paul Samuelson. Other large amounts of correspondence and other materials relate to Davidson's editorial work with many major economics journals, including the Journal of Post Keynesian Economics, which he founded; these folders typically contain correspondence between Davidson, journal referees, and authors. In one group of folders, Davidson engages with other colleagues in sometimes heated exchanges about bias in professional journals. In addition to correspondence with colleagues and authors, the files also contain correspondence related to academic departments where Davidson held positions. Reflecting his broad background, the papers also document Davidson's involvement with politics (see the Congress folder) and consultancy work for an energy company in his early career (the Oil and Energy folders), and his role as an active public figure, documented by letters to the editor for various maistream publications.
Subject Headings
Arestis, Philip, 1941-; Bernstein, Peter L.; Chick, Victoria; Clower, Robert W.; Davidson, Paul, 1930-; Eichner, Alfred S.; Eisner, Robert; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-; Harcourt, Geoffrey Colin; Hicks, John Richard, Sir, 1904-; Kregel, J. A.; Meltzer, Allan H.; Moore, Basil J.; Nell, Edward J.; Pasinetti, Luigi L.; Patinkin, Don; Robinson, Joan, 1903-; Samuelson, Paul A. (Paul Anthony), 1915-2009; Thirlwall, A. P.; Tobin, James, 1918-; Weintraub, Sidney, 1914-; University of Tennessee, Knoxville. College of Business Administration. Economics Department; Economists -- Correspondence; Economics -- United States; Energy economics and policy; International finance; Keynesian economics; Monetary policy; Neoclassical school of economics -- History; Post-Keynesian economics; Post-Keynesian economics -- Periodicals
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1961-2004 and undated, (26 boxes)
  Exchanges reflect professional relationships Davidson maintained with colleagues in the United States, Italy, England, Japan, and other countries. There are also many folders of correspondence with academic institutions, media organizations, presses, and publishers, much of which stems from Davidson's many editorial roles for professional journals and other publications. Smaller amounts of correspondence relate to conferences and lectures. The more abundant files include corresponde with Milton Friedman, Geoff Harcourt, Sir John Hicks, Jan Kregel, and Sidney Weintraub; also, there is significant correspondence with economists whose papers are also held at Duke University, such as Clower, Patinkin, Perlman, and Samuelson. Arranged in alphabetical order by correpondent, publication, or topic; each alphabetical sequence is initiated by folders of routine or single-letter correpondence filed by letter rather than by name. There is one file of correspondence containing letters with no last names indicated.
  - A Miscellaneous, 1974-2000 (Box 1)
  - Abramovitz, Moses, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Ackley, Gardner, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Adelman, Irma, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Adelman, M. A., 1961-1980 (Box 1)
  - Aggregate Supply and Demand, 1964-1979 (Box 1)
  - Akerlof, George A., 1986 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Lamar, 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Robert J., 1970-1991 (Box 1)
  - Allen and Unwin, 1979-1985 (Box 1)
  - American Economic Association (disputes about bias in journals), 1968-1996 (Box 1)
  - American Economic Association Meetings, 1967-1993 (Box 1)
  - American Economics Review, 1962-2004, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - American Journal of Economics and Sociology, 1998 (Box 1)
  - American for Democratic Action (ADA), 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Andreatta, Nino, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Appelbaum, Eileen, 1981-1989 (Box 1)
  - Arena, Richard, 1985-1993 (Box 1)
  - Arestis, Philip, 1985-1993, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Arestis, Philip, 1985-1993, (2 of 2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Arrow, Kenneth J., 1972-1974 (Box 2)
  - Ashenfelter, Orley, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Asimakopulos, Tom, 1976-1993 (Box 2)
  - B Miscellaneous, 1967-1996, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Bab, Herbert, 1978-1983 (Box 2)
  - Baker, Russel (NYTimes), 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Balinky, Alexandra, 1972-1998 (Box 2)
  - Balough, Thomas, 1978-1982 (Box 2)
  - Banca Nazionale Del Lavoro, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
  - Banks, David (NIST) 1997 (Box 2)
  - Banks, Ferdinand E., 1985 (Box 2)
  - Barone, Charles, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Barrere, Alain, 1983-1986 (Box 2)
  - Bartel, Richard D., 1979-1993 (Box 2)
  - Basic Books (Kessler), 1978-1989 (Box 2)
  - Basil Blackwell Publishers, 1979-1983 (Box 2)
  - Basseer, Potkin A., 1984 (Box 2)
  - Bator, Francis, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Baumol, William J. 1988-1996 (Box 2)
  - Bausor, Randall, 1985-1996 (Box 2)
  - Bell, Daniel, 1979-1989 (Box 2)
  - Berglund, Per Gunnar, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
  - Berkowitz, Monroe, 1967-1984 (Box 2)
  - Berman, Barbara, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Bernstein, Peter, 1980-2002, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Bhaduri, Amit, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
  - Blackwood, G. H., 1985 (Box 3)
  - Blatt, John, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
  - Blaug, Mark (Who's Who in Economics), 1982-1999 (Box 3)
  - Blecker, Robert A., 1989-1997 (Box 3)
  - Blinder, Alan S., 1984-2000 (Box 3)
  - Blohm, Bernard (Welt am Sonntag), 1997 (Box 3)
  - Bloomfield, Arthur T., 1968-1994 (Box 3)
  - Bodkin, Ronald G., 1978-1999 (Box 3)
  - Bohm, Bernhard, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Bohnsack, Ken, 1992-1997 (Box 3)
  - Bonin, John P., 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Book reviews, 1970-1988 (Box 3)
  - Bordon, Therese (World Development), 2000 (Box 3)
  - Borts, George, 1968-1979 (Box 3)
  - Boston Sunday Globe, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Boulding, Kenneth E., 1968-1988 (Box 3)
  - Bowles, Samuel, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
  - Brannon, Gerald M., 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Brazelton, Robert, 1978-1991 (Box 3)
  - Brazil, 1978-2002 (Box 3)
  - Breimyer, Harold, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Brenner, Y. S., 1988-1990 (Box 3)
  - Bresser Pereira, Luiz Carlos, 1989-2000 (Box 4)
  - Bretton Woods Conference, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Brockway, George, 1983-2000 (Box 4)
  - Bronfenbrenner, Martin, 1961-1980 (Box 4)
  - Brookings Institution, 1974-1985 (Box 4)
  - Brothwell, John F., 1969-1991 (Box 4)
  - Bufalo, Enzo Del, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Burkett, John T., 1989 (Box 4)
  - Business Week, 1975-1981 (Box 4)
  - C Miscellaneous, 1969-1996 (Box 4)
  - Cambridge Journal of Economics, 1977-1998 (Box 4)
  - Cambridge University, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1977-1995 (Box 4)
  - Campolongo, Albert, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Canterbery, Ray, 1983-1995 (Box 4)
  - Caracas, 1980-1987 (Box 4)
  - Caribbean, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Carleton College, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Carvalho, Fernando, 1983-1996 (Box 4)
  - Cassidy, John (The New Yorker), 1995-2004 (Box 4)
  - Center for a New Democracy, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Center for Democratic Policy, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Cesarini, Francesco, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Challenge Magazine, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
  - Champernowne, D. G., 1972-1975 (Box 4)
  - Chemical Engineering Progress Journal, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Chick, Victoria, 1973-2000 (Box 4)
  - China, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - Cho, Young, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Christensen, Paul P., 1979 (Box 5)
  - Cicarelli, James, 1980-1989 (Box 5)
  - Cicchetti, Charles, 1969-1996 (Box 5)
  - Clower, Robert, 1971-1998, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Colander, David, 1976-1997 (Box 5)
  - Conferences, 1973-2000 (Box 5)
  - Congress, 1968-1999, (3 folders) (Box 5)
  - Consumer's Union, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Controversies in Post Keynesian Economics 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Cornford, Andrew, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Cornwall, John, 1977-1991 (Box 5)
  - Cotta, Alain, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Critical Review Journal, 1989-1994 (Box 5)
  - Curry, Karen (CBS News), 1979 (Box 5)
  - Curzio, Alberto Quadrio, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
  - D Miscellaneous, 1967-1998, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Darity, William, Jr., 1979-1996 (Box 6)
  - Davidson, Greg, 1996-1999 (Box 6)
  - Davila, José Gerardo, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Davis, John (Review of Social Economy), 1998 (Box 6)
  - Dell, Sidney, 1975-1989 (Box 6)
  - Denoel, François, 1977-1980 (Box 6)
  - Deprez, Johan, 1985-1997 (Box 6)
  - Dequech, David, 1995-2002 (Box 6)
  - Diaz, Carlos Obregon, 1979-1984 (Box 6)
  - Dickens, William T., 1979 (Box 6)
  - Dillard, Dudley, 1975-1991 (Box 6)
  - Dow, Sheila, 1987-1996 (Box 6)
  - Drew University Keynes Day, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Duke University, 1979-1991 (Box 6)
  - Dunn, Stephen, 1997-2000 (Box 6)
  - Dunning, J. H. (Reading University), 1968-1972 (Box 6)
  - Durell Journal of Money and Banking, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Dvorak, Eldon J. (Western Economic Association), 1979-1982 (Box 6)
  - Dymski, Gary, 1989-1995 (Box 6)
  - E Miscellaneous, 1968-2002 (Box 6)
  - Eastern Economic Association, 1983-1988 (Box 6)
  - Eastern Economic Journal, 1982-1993 (Box 6)
  - Eastern Economic Meetings, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Eatwell, John, 1976-1996 (Box 6)
  - Econometrica, 1966-1968 (Box 6)
  - Économie Appliqueés, 1977-1988 (Box 6)
  - Economic Journal (Carter, C. F.), 1963-1973 (Box 6)
  - Economic Journal, 1967-2003, (1-2 of 3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Economic Journal, 1967-2003, (3 of 3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Economic Policy Institute, 1985-1994 (Box 7)
  - Economica, 1972-1974 (Box 7)
  - Economics for a Civilized Society, 1988-1996 (Box 7)
  - Economics for a Civilized Society (Japanese edition), 1988-1996 (Box 7)
  - Economist Magazine, 1990-2002 (Box 7)
  - Ecuador, 1977-2003 (Box 7)
  - Ecuador Central Bank, 1978-1979 (Box 7)
  - Eichner, Alfred, 1972-1989, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Eisner, Robert, 1978-1996 (Box 7)
  - Elliott, Larry (Guardian), 1998-2000 (Box 7)
  - Elgar, Edward, 1987-1998, (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Encyclopedic Dictionary of Political Economy, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Encyclopedia of Economics, 1979-1991 (Box 8)
  - Encyclopedia Nationale des Sciences, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Energy, 1966-1987, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Energy Journal, 1966-1983 (Box 8)
  - Ergodicity, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Espinosa, Rodrigo, 1979-1981 (Box 8)
  - Etzioni, Amitai, 1985-1989 (Box 8)
  - Evolutionary Economics Association, 1985 (Box 8)
  - F Miscellaneous, 1963-1997 (Box 8)
  - Falk, Larry, 1975-1990 (Box 8)
  - Fazzari, Steve, 1989-1998 (Box 8)
  - Federal Reserve Bank, 1977-1986 (Box 8)
  - Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland, 1993-1994 (Box 8)
  - Feiwel, George, 1976-1979 (Box 8)
  - Felix, David, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Fels, Rendigs, 1967-1974 (Box 8)
  - Fenwick, Millicent, 1977 (Box 9)
  - Ferber, Robert, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
  - Ferguson, Allen R., 1972-1984 (Box 9)
  - Fernandes, Santiago, 1975-1987 (Box 9)
  - Ferrari, Fernando Filho, 1993-1997 (Box 9)
  - Filc, Wolfgang, 1997-1998 (Box 9)
  - Finance Motive, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Fleming, Miles, 1966-1978 (Box 9)
  - Forstater, Mathew, 1996-1997 (Box 9)
  - Friedman, Benjamin, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Friedman, Milton, 1967-1979, (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Frowen, Stephen, 1980-1996 (Box 9)
  - Fukudogawa, Yoji, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
  - Fusfeld, Dan, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
  - G Miscellaneous, 1969-1996 (Box 9)
  - Gaffney, Mason, 1983-1992 (Box 9)
  - Galbraith, James K., 1978-2002 (Box 9)
  - Galbraith, John K., 1972-2000, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Galbraith, John K., 1972-2000, (2 of 2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Gapinski, James, 1985-1990 (Box 10)
  - Garegnani, Pierangelo, 1979-1981 (Box 10)
  - Garretsen, Harry, 1991-1993 (Box 10)
  - Garrison, Charles, 1998 (Box 10)
  - Garst, Tom, 1998-2003 (Box 10)
  - Gas Producers Association, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
  - Gettysburg College, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Gershenberg, Irving, 1972 (Box 10)
  - Giarini, Orio, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Gide Conference, 1993-1994 (Box 10)
  - Gilbert, Bob (University of Tennessee publicity), 1992-1993 (Box 10)
  - Glassbord State College (Rowen College), 1989 (Box 10)
  - Glickman, Murray, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Godley, Wynne, 1978-1996 (Box 10)
  - Golden, Claudia, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Goldfeld, Steve, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Goldstein, Suzanne, 1989-1990 (Box 10)
  - Goodhart, Charles, 1979-1988 (Box 10)
  - Goodstein, Marvin, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Gordon, Kermit, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Gordon, Myron J., 1980-1993 (Box 10)
  - Gordon, Robert J., 1971-1974 (Box 10)
  - Gore, Albert, 1979-1993 (Box 10)
  - Gower Publishing Group, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Gracelli, Aldemir, 1987-1990 (Box 10)
  - Graduate students, 1978-1992 (Box 10)
  - Graham, Edward M., 1977-1980 (Box 10)
  - Gram, Harvey, 1982-1988 (Box 10)
  - Gray, Peter H., 1972-1996 (Box 10)
  - Greenman, John, 1968-1979 (Box 10)
  - Greenspan, Alan, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Greer, Bill, 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - Greer, Douglas F., 1974 (Box 10)
  - Grubel, Herb, 1968-1974 (Box 10)
  - Guardian Newspaper, 1998 (Box 10)
  - Gurley, John, 1963-1972 (Box 10)
  - H Miscellaneous, 1968-2002 (Box 10)
  - Hahn, Frank, 1967-1996 (Box 11)
  - Halevy, Joseph, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Halstead Press, 1972-1982 (Box 11)
  - Hamouda, Omar, F., 1986-1988 (Box 11)
  - Harcourt, Geoff, 1967-2000, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Harris, Donald, 1969-1990 (Box 11)
  - Harrod, Roy, 1964-1970 (Box 11)
  - Harvey, John T., 1989-1992 (Box 11)
  - Hart, Peter, 1967-1969 (Box 11)
  - Hart, Philip A. (Congress), 1975 (Box 11)
  - Hawaii Public Utilities, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Heilbroner, Robert, 1991-1999 (Box 11)
  - Henwood, Doug, 1994-1999 (Box 11)
  - Hicks, John, 1975-1981, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Hieke, Hubert, 1989-1996 (Box 11)
  - Hillard, John, 1988-1993 (Box 11)
  - Hines, Albert G., 1970-1972 (Box 11)
  - Hirschman, Albert O., 1977-1978 (Box 11)
  - History of Political Economy Journal, 1987-2000 (Box 11)
  - Holt, Ric, 1988-1995 (Box 11)
  - Hotson, John H., 1968-1990 (Box 11)
  - I Miscellaneous, 1977-1994 (Box 11)
  - International Monetary Fund (IMF), 1999 (Box 12)
  - Inflation, 1972-1985 (Box 12)
  - Institute for Advanced Studies Princeton, 1978-1985 (Box 12)
  - Institute for Advanced Studies Vienna, 1977-1984 (Box 12)
  - International Economic Policy Association, 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - International Summer School Trieste, 1980 (Box 12)
  - International Money and the Real World, 1982-1992 (Box 12)
  - International Money and the Real World et al., 1979-1983 (Box 12)
  - J Miscellaneous, 1967-2003 (Box 12)
  - Janeway, William, 1991-2002 (Box 12)
  - Japan, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Jayawardena, Lal (Sri Lanka), 1999 (Box 12)
  - Jensen, Hans, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - Job Offers, 1969-1978 (Box 12)
  - Journal of Economic Issues, 1978-1993 (Box 12)
  - Journal of Economic Literature, 1975-2000 (Box 12)
  - Journal of Economic Perspectives, 1987-1993, (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Journal of Economic and Social Policy, 1997 (Box 12)
  - Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking, 1970-1982 (Box 12)
  - Journal of Political Economy, 1969-1972 (Box 12)
  - Journal of Post Keynesian Economics, 1977-1996, (1-2 of 6 folders) (Box 12)
  - Journal of Post Keynesian Economics, 1977-1996, (3-6 of 6 folders) (Box 13)
  - K Miscellaneous, 1968-1992 (Box 13)
  - Kahn, Alfred, 1968-1981 (Box 13)
  - Kahn, Richard, 1967 (Box 13)
  - Kaiser, Gordon (Canada vs. Major Oil Companies), 1977-1990 (Box 13)
  - Kaldor, Nicholas, 1967-1989 (Box 13)
  - Kalecki, Michl, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Kaplan, Jacob, 1995 (Box 13)
  - Kato, Hirotaka, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Katzner, Donald, 1974-1992 (Box 13)
  - Keen, Steve, 1995 (Box 13)
  - Kennedy, Edward, 1977-1979 (Box 13)
  - Kennen, Peter, 1994-1998 (Box 13)
  - Keynes Centenary Celebration, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Keynes, J. M. - Various correspondence and print material, 1987-1996 (Box 13)
  - Keynes, Milo, 1997 (Box 13)
  - Kindleberger, Charles, 2000 (Box 13)
  - King, John, 1992-1997 (Box 13)
  - Knowledge Products, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Kredit and Kapital Journal, 1981-1986 (Box 14)
  - Kregel, Jan A., 1969-1993, (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - Kriesler, Peter, 1989-1990 (Box 14)
  - Krugman, Paul R., 1991 (Box 14)
  - Kurz, Mordecai, 1999 (Box 14)
  - L Miscellaneous, 1973-2002 (Box 14)
  - Lackman, Conway, 1977-1982 (Box 14)
  - Lachman, Werner, 1971-1979 (Box 14)
  - Lachmann, L. M., 1975 (Box 14)
  - Laidler, David, 1989-1992 (Box 14)
  - Land Economics Journal, 1975 (Box 14)
  - Larsson, Sven, 1991-2000 (Box 14)
  - Lavoie, Marc, 1982 (Box 14)
  - Lawson, Tony, 1986-1996 (Box 14)
  - Lee, Frederic, 1981-1999 (Box 14)
  - Lee, Hoesung, 1973-1992 (Box 14)
  - Leeds University Conferences, 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Legge, John, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Lehrman Institute, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Leibenstein, Harvey, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Leijonhufvud, Axel, 1974-1979 (Box 14)
  - Liepmann, Peter, 1981-1982 (Box 14)
  - Leopold, Joseph, 1991 (Box 14)
  - Lerner, Abba, 1968-1976 (Box 14)
  - Letters of recommendation (various), 1966-1993, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Letters to Editor, 1970-2000, (3 folders) (Box 15)
  - Levine, Larry, 1987-1991 (Box 15)
  - Levy Institute (Bard College), 1988-1998 (Box 15)
  - Levy, Leon, 1993-1998 (Box 15)
  - Lima, Gilberto Tadeu, 1989-1990 (Box 15)
  - Los Angeles Times, undated (Box 15)
  - Loescher, Samuel, 1968-1987 (Box 15)
  - M Miscellaneous, 1971-2002, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Macavoy, Paul W., 1974 (Box 15)
  - Maclachlan, Fiona, 1980-1988 (Box 15)
  - Macmillan Press, 1971-1996, (1-2 of 3 folders) (Box 15)
  - Macmillan Press, 1971-1996, (3 of 3 folders) (Box 16)
  - Maital, Shlomo, 1978-1983 (Box 16)
  - Malisoff, Harry, 1964 (Box 16)
  - Marshall Society (Cambridge University), 1990 (Box 16)
  - Mason, Will E., 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Matzner, Egon, 1985-1990 (Box 16)
  - Mayhew, Anne, 1989-1996 (Box 16)
  - McCloskey, D., undated (Box 16)
  - McCombie, John, 1994-2002 (Box 16)
  - McGovern, George, 1972-1978 (Box 16)
  - McGraw-Hill Encyclopedia of Economics, 1972-1993 (Box 16)
  - McKinnon, Ronald I., 1992 (Box 16)
  - McNeil-Lehrer TV, 1979 (Box 16)
  - Meade, James, 1985 (Box 16)
  - Meltzer, Alan H., 1966-2003 (Box 16)
  - Mexico, 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Milberg, Will, 1985-1997 (Box 16)
  - Mills, Gordon, 1977-1978 (Box 16)
  - Minow, Newton N., 1971 (Box 16)
  - Minsky, Hyman, 1970-1996 (Box 16)
  - Moggridge, Donald, 1973-1995 (Box 16)
  - Moore, Basil, 1971-1996, (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - Money and the Real World, 1971-1992 (Box 16)
  - Money and the Real World (Japanese Edition), 1979 (Box 16)
  - Morehouse, Ward, 1984-1989 (Box 17)
  - Mosler, Warren, 1996-2002 (Box 17)
  - N Miscellaneous, 1967-1990 (Box 17)
  - Naples, Michele, 1988-1991 (Box 17)
  - The Nation, 1993-1996 (Box 17)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1968-1986 (Box 17)
  - National Dividend Foundation, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Natural Resources, 1966-1983 (Box 17)
  - National Science Foundation, 1978-1984 (Box 17)
  - Nebraska Journal of Economics, 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - Nell, Edward, 1975-1994 (Box 17)
  - New Jersey State, 1973-1978 (Box 17)
  - New Leader Magazine, 1984-1995 (Box 17)
  - New School University, 1996 (Box 17)
  - New York Times, 1979-2003 (Box 17)
  - New York University Press, 1996 (Box 17)
  - Newsweek Magazine, 1995 (Box 17)
  - Niggle, Chris, 1991 (Box 17)
  - Nightingale, Leonard, 1976-1998 (Box 17)
  - Notre Dame University, 1980-1981 (Box 17)
  - O Miscellaneous, 1978-1990 (Box 17)
  - Ogata, Toshio, 1982-1996 (Box 17)
  - Oil, 1969-1983 (Box 17)
  - Oxford Economic Papers, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Oxford University Press, 1977-1980 (Box 17)
  - Owen, Wyn, 1967-1968 (Box 17)
  - P Miscellaneous, 1977-2002 (Box 17)
  - Paganetto, Luigi, 1979-1981 (Box 17)